regents.ac.uk 2019-03-30

# Privacy and cookies | Regent's University London

Regent's University London is committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.

This Privacy Notice explains when and why we collect personal information about people who visit our website, how we use it, the conditions under which we may disclose it to others and how we keep it secure.

Any personal information collected will be processed and safeguarded in accordance with the Data Protection Act 2018 which incorporated the General Data Protection Regulation (EU 2016/670) (GDPR).

Regent’s University London is the 'data controller' as defined by the Data Protection Act 2018. Personal information will only be collected and/or processed by Regent’s University London in accordance with the Act.

This Policy is subject to change to meet new legislative requirements, so please check this page occasionally to ensure that you’re happy with any changes.

Any questions regarding this Policy and our privacy practices should be sent by email to [privacy@regents.ac.uk](mailto:privacy@regents.ac.uk) or in writing to Governance Office, Regent's University London, Inner Circle, Regent's Park, London, NW1 4NS.

## Student Collection Notice

Each year we are required to send some of the information we hold about you to HESA (the Higher Education Statistics Agency). HESA uses this information to publish statistics about students in higher education and to provide services and information to other organisations, and to conduct surveys such as the National Student Survey (NSS) and the Graduate Outcomes Survey (GOS). All uses of your HESA information must comply with the General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679 (GDPR) and the Data Protection Act 2018.

  To find out more about HESA, how and why they process your data, the legal basis for this processing, and your rights under data protection legislation, you can access HESA’s Student Collection Notice via the following link: [www.hesa.ac.uk/fpn](https://www.hesa.ac.uk/fpn)

## Who we are?

Regent's University London is a private non-profit university located in London, United Kingdom. The university has an international student body with students coming from 140 countries overall. The University has its campus in Regent's Park, Central London.

## Our commitment to securing your personal data

Regent’s University London undertakes to maintain your personal data in secure conditions. Your personal data will be disclosed to staff and agents of the University in order to support our services to you; this is done on a need-to-know basis and all staff are made aware of the procedures they must follow to ensure your data is protected.

## What personal information is collected from you?

We collect personally identifiable information about you through:

  * the use of enquiry, application and registration forms;
  * your purchase of any our products or services;
  * information that we request from you regarding your use of our service; and
  * your use of our website.

The elements of your information that we collect may include:

  * Name
  * Home address and phone number
  * Mobile telephone number
  * E-mail address
  * IP address
  * Date of birth
  * Educational history, work experience and other information from your CV if you provide this to us
  * Attendance and absence
  * Grades and academic performance
  * Health records
  * Personal information from selected partner 3rd parties (working on our behalf)
  * Social media accounts
  * Usage statistics
  * Website pages accessed

We also collect information about you and your visit to our website automatically using Cookies.

Please see Appendix 1 for further details of our website usage information that is collected using cookies.

Full details of all the personal information we collect, the purpose for collecting along with the lawful basis for processing can be found in our Record of Processing. Any questions regarding the personal information we collect and the reasons we collect it should be sent by email to [privacy@regents.ac.uk](mailto:privacy@regents.ac.uk) or in writing to Governance Office, Regent's University London, Inner Circle, Regent's Park, London, NW1 4NS.

## How is your information used?

When you make an application to join the University we need to know your basic personal data in order to process your application. We will not collect any personal data from you that we do not need in order to provide and oversee this services to you.

Regent’s University London will use your personal information for a number of purposes including the following:

  * process an application to work for us;
  * to carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into by you and us;
  * processing applications, registrations and enquiries;
  * maintaining your student record (including personal and academic details);
  * managing the academic processes (including teaching, exam board meetings, and awarding degrees);
  * providing advice and support;
  * providing our customers with a personalised service (including IT user and library accounts etc.);
  * conducting market research surveys and fundraising surveys;
  * conducting fundraising campaigns;
  * alumni development initiatives;
  * conducting surveys;
  * allowing users to participate in interactive features of our service, where they choose to do so;
  * to personalise your repeat visits to our website;
  * to carry out statistical analysis of trends in data;
  * communicating prior to you applying and joining Regent’s University London for the purposes of marketing;
  * providing you with information about products and services we offer (if you agree to receive such information);
  * to contact you should you withdraw your application to seek your reason for doing so (and to provide support and advice where appropriate); 
  * to fulfil our statutory obligations through statutory returns and reporting to sponsors and government agencies such as HESA (Higher Education Statistics Agency) and the Home Office’;
  * where your data is disclosed to a third party, this is done in accordance with the provisions of The Data Protection Act and GDPR.

We will never sell, distribute or release your information to third parties unless we are required to do so as part of our statutory reporting duties.

We also use information in aggregate form (so that no individual user is identified by name):

  * to build up marketing profiles;
  * to aid strategic development;
  * to manage our relationship with advertisers; and
  * to audit usage of the site.

We use technology on the registration, application and enquiry pages of our website, which may record user movements, including page scrolling, mouse clicks and text entered. The data we collect in this way helps us to identify usability issues, to improve the assistance and technical support we can provide to users and is also used for aggregated and statistical reporting purposes.

## Marketing

We would like to send you information about products and services of ours which may be of interest to you. If you have consented to receive marketing, you may opt out at a later date. You have a right at any time to stop us from contacting you for marketing purposes. If you no longer wish to be contacted for marketing purposes, please contact us by email to [privacy@regents.ac.uk](mailto:privacy@regents.ac.uk) or in writing to Governance Office, Regent's University London, Inner Circle, Regent's Park, London, NW1 4NS.

## Alumni and Fundraising

We have a separate privacy policy for alumni and fundraising activities, available at the alumni section of our website. https://www.regents.ac.uk/about/alumni/supporting-regents/spirit-of-regents-fund

## How long will we keep your information for?

We will hold your personal information on our systems for as long as is necessary for the relevant activity, or as long as is set out in any relevant contract you hold with us. We regularly review the retention periods for personal information and we will securely destroy the out of retention information line with our retention and destruction policy.  
Our approved retention schedule is available from [privacy@regents.ac.uk](mailto:privacy@regents.ac.uk).

Key personal information retention periods are:

  * Student Data: We retain all student records for a period of 7 years from the date a student completed their studies. This date is determined as the date on which the leaver’s form has been completed or the last date of the term in which the student left. Some data such as transcripts of student final results may be retained in perpetuity.
  * Prospective Student Data: Where an application form has been completed and/or interview notes have been made but the applicant does not enrol then their data will be retained for a period of 1 year from the date of application or interview whichever is the later.
  * Staff Data: We are required under UK Tax Law to keep basic personal data (name, address, etc.) for 6 years from the end of employment after which time it will be destroyed. Some data (such as Health records) will be retained for a longer period dependant on purpose.

## Working with Third Parties

Regent’s University London works with third party organisations and we will share personal information with them for the purposes of completing tasks and providing services to you on our behalf (for example to register you with an Awarding Bodies).

## Links to other websites

The Regent’s University London website contains hyperlinks to websites owned and operated by third parties. These third party websites have their own privacy policies, and are also likely to use cookies, and we therefore urge you to review them. They will govern the use of personal information you submit when visiting these websites, which may also be collected by cookies.

We do not accept any responsibility or liability for the privacy practices of such third party websites and your use of such websites is at your own risk.

## Disclosure of your Personal Information

Information about you may be disclosed to other organisations as required by law, for crime prevention or detection purposes, or in order to comply with our obligations as a sponsor of migrants by the Home Office.

We may also transfer your personal information to a third party if we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation or to enforce or apply our terms of use or to protect the rights or safety of our staff and students. However, we will take steps with the aim of ensuring that your privacy rights continue to be protected.

Disclosures will also be made by Regent’s University London as outlined below:

a)To sponsors, government agencies and present or potential employers. One such body is the Home Office (for international students) and the Higher Education Statistics Agency (HESA); further information about the uses for which HESA processes personal data can be found on the HESA website at <http://www.hesa.ac.uk/collection-notices/>;

b) Your contact details may also be passed to statutory reporting bodies and sector agencies such as the Higher Education Funding Council (HEFCE) (or successor bodies such as the Office for Students) for the purpose of administering the national student survey;

c) To Regents University London’s agents for the purpose of administering our own surveys;

d) Sector agencies such as UCAS;

e) Where a programme of study leads to a qualification recognised by a professional body Regent’s University London will disclose relevant information to that body;

f) Statements of student status will be provided on request to Council Tax Registration Officers;

g) To the Student Loans Company;

h) To debt collection agencies acting on behalf of Regent’s University London in the event that you owe money to us;

i) Release of results to former schools/colleges;

j) Students on study visits to partner institutions and placement providers (both UK and abroad);

k) Names will be included in pass lists;

l) Staff secondments and staff mobility;

m) Crime and taxation – the University may share your personal data where this is for the purposes of detecting or preventing crime or taxation purposes (e.g., eligibility for council tax exemptions); and

n) Outsourcing – Regent’s University London outsources some of its processes and provide students’ personal data to third party companies for these purposes.

## Who has access to your information?

All the personal data we process is processed by our staff in the UK however for the purposes of IT hosting and maintenance this information is located on servers within the European Union.

We have contractual relationships with selected third party providers to deliver services, and therefore process your personal information on our behalf.

If you have any questions about our third party and the personal information they collect and the reasons they collect it should be sent by email to [privacy@regents.ac.uk](mailto:privacy@regents.ac.uk) or in writing to Governance Office, Regent's University London, Inner Circle, Regent's Park, London, NW1 4NS.

No third parties have access to your personal data unless we have a contractual relationship with them to deliver services on our behalf, or the law allows them to do so. We will not sell or rent your information to third parties. We will not share your information with third parties for marketing purposes.

## Security precautions in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of your information

When you give us personal information, we take steps to ensure that it’s treated securely. Any sensitive information (such as credit or debit card details) is encrypted and protected. When you are on a secure page, a lock icon will appear on the bottom of web browsers such as Microsoft Internet Explorer.

Non-sensitive details (your email address etc.) are transmitted normally over the Internet, and this can never be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of any information you transmit to us, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your information, we make our best effort to ensure its security on our systems. Where we have given (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our websites, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share your password with anyone.

## Am I able to see what data you hold on me and how it is processed?

You have the right to obtain confirmation that your data is being processed lawfully and to access your own personal data. There is no charge for this service unless the request is considered manifestly unfounded or excessive, particularly where it is repetitive. Then Regent's University London may charge a ‘reasonable fee’ which may also apply should further copies of the same information be requested. This fee will be based on the administrative cost of providing the information.

Once your identity has been verified then you will be provided with the information held within one month of the receipt of the request. This period may be extended to a further two months where requests are complex or numerous however you will be informed of this within one month of the request being received with an explanation why an extension is necessary.

## How you can access and update your information?

The accuracy of your information is important to us. We’re working on ways to make it easier for you to review and correct the information that we hold about you. In the meantime, if you change email address, or any of the other information we hold is inaccurate or out of date, please email to [privacy@regents.ac.uk](mailto:privacy@regents.ac.uk) or in writing to Governance Office, Regent's University London, Inner Circle, Regent's Park, London, NW1 4NS.

## What can I do if I believe the information you have about me is inaccurate?

If at any point you believe the information we process on you is incorrect you can request to see this information and have it corrected or deleted. If you wish to raise a complaint on how we handled your personal data, you can contact us to have the matter investigated. please email to [privacy@regents.ac.uk](mailto:privacy@regents.ac.uk) or in writing to Governance Office, Regent's University London, Inner Circle, Regent's Park, London, NW1 4NS.

If you are not satisfied with our response or believe we are processing your personal data not in accordance with the law you can complain to the Information Commissioner’s Office [https://ico.org.uk](https://ico.org.uk/)

## What can I do if I no longer wish the University to process my data?

If you decide that you no longer wish to attend the University before enrolment/employment has taken place, then you have the right to withdraw your consent for data processing to take place and if request it that your data to be erased. If you wish to exercise this right then please email to [privacy@regents.ac.uk](mailto:privacy@regents.ac.uk) or in writing to Governance Office, Regent's University London, Inner Circle, Regent's Park, London, NW1 4NS.

## 16 or Under

We are concerned to protect the privacy of children aged 16 or under. If you are aged 16 or under‚ please get your parent/guardian's permission beforehand whenever you provide us with personal information.

## Transferring your information outside of Europe

As part of the services offered to you through this website, the information which you provide to us may be transferred to countries outside the European Union (“EU”). By way of example, this may happen if any of our servers are from time to time located in a country outside of the EU. These countries may not have similar data protection laws to the UK. By submitting your personal data, you’re agreeing to this transfer, storing or processing. If we transfer your information outside of the EU in this way, we will take steps to ensure that appropriate security measures are taken with the aim of ensuring that your privacy rights continue to be protected as outlined in this Policy.

## Changes to our privacy policy

We keep our privacy policy under regular review and we will place any updates on this web page. This privacy policy was last updated on May 2018.

## How to contact us

Please contact us if you have any question s about our privacy policy or information we hold about you:

  * by email at: [privacy@regents.ac.uk](mailto:privacy@regents.ac.uk); or
  * in writing to: Governance Office, Regent's University London, Inner Circle, Regent's Park, London, NW1 4NS.  

Further information on the cookies used on this site
